const questions = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "What is the traditional Igbo political system called?",
    options: ["Arochukwu", "Eze", "Ohanaeze", "Umunna"],
    answer: "Umunna",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "What was the primary pre-colonial occupation of the Igbo people?",
    options: ["Fishing", "Trading", "Agriculture", "Weaving"],
    answer: "Agriculture",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "What is the name of the Igbo traditional belief system?",
    options: ["Odinani", "Sango", "Ifa", "Urhobo"],
    answer: "Odinani",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: "In which modern-day Nigerian state can you find the famous Arochukwu Long Juju shrine?",
    options: ["Abia", "Imo", "Anambra", "Enugu"],
    answer: "Abia"
  },
  {
      id: 5,
    question: "What is the name of the traditional Igbo marketplace gathering held every four days?",
    options: ["Nkwo", "Eke", "Orie", "Afor"],
    answer: "Eke",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: "What is the pre-colonial Igbo political system characterized by?",
    options: [
      "Centralized monarchy",
      "Decentralized democracy",
      "Military dictatorship",
      "Feudal lords",
    ],
    answer: "Decentralized democracy",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "Which region in Nigeria is predominantly inhabited by the Igbo people?",
    options: ["North Central", "North East", "South West", "South East"],
    answer: "South East",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: "Which major river is significant in Igbo land?",
    options: ["River Benue", "River Niger", "River Osun", "River Cross"],
    answer: "River Niger",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: "What is the traditional religion of the Igbo people called?",
    options: [
      "Sango",
      "Odinani",
      "Ifa",
      "Traditional Yoruba religion",
    ],
    answer: "Odinani",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: "Which Nigerian civil war leader was of Igbo origin?",
    options: [
      "Murtala Ramat Mohammed",
      "Yakubu Gowon",
      "Chukwuemeka Odumegwu Ojukwu",
      "Benjamin Adekunle",
    ],
    answer: "Chukwuemeka Odumegwu Ojukwu",
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question: "What is the primary occupation of the Igbo people?",
    options: ["Fishing", "Farming", "Hunting", "Trading"],
    answer: "Farming",
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question: "Which festival is celebrated to mark the beginning of the Igbo calendar?",
    options: ["Iri-ji", "Argungu", "Ojude Oba", "Eyo"],
    answer: "Iri-ji",
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question: "What is the name of the highest-ranking spirit in the Igbo traditional religion?",
    options: ["Amadioha", "Chukwu", "Agwu", "Ala"],
    answer: "Chukwu",
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: "Which of these names is an Igbo name for God?",
    options: ["Chineke", "Eledumare", "Obatala", "Sango"],
    answer: "Chineke",
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: "Which of these is a popular masquerade in Igbo culture?",
    options: ["Eyo", "Mmanwu", "Gelede", "Ijele"],
    answer: "Mmanwu",
  },
  // Add more questions here
];

export default questions;
